# MAHMOUD MIRANI

Portfolio: mirani.se

**J** +46 76 268 1910

mahso@kth.se

in LinkedIn

github.com/MoodMirani

#### INTRO

While studying at KTH, I worked part-time in We Know IT, which is an IT consultancy company. After that I worked as a developer in TeamEngine. My goal is to work at a place where I can create new digital applications and contribute to a fun office culture. Make sure to check out my personal portfolio, linked above.

### **EDUCATION**

#### **Master of Science in Engineering**

Aug. 2017 - Dec. 2023

University: KTH Royal Institute of Technology

Stockholm

- Major: Interactive Media Technology
- I studied programming, algorithms, machinelearning, product development, math, physics and some economi.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

React Developer Jan. 2023 – Sept. 2023

Company: TeamEngine

Stockholm

- I Learned working with a DevOps workflow while developing a notifications panel in Reactjs including automated Cypress tests.
- The panel has been deployed and is currently being used by thousands of customers who responded with good feedback.

Regional Manager May 2021 - Nov. 2022

Company: We Know IT

Stockholm

- I learned project management as I managed 5 clients, the project with the most value was worth 450 000 SEK.
- I was a boardmember for the strategic leadership of the company, during this year, our revenue grew by 100%, from 2.5M to 5M.
- I learned Agile Software development and Scrum as I lead 5 teams, totalling 11 developers and 2 designers.
- I learned how to pitch and communicate as I contributed to sales by conducting meetings with customers.
- I started taking a more technical managerial role in the company as I wrote documentation for a standardised project plan including set phases for testing and progress reflections. This increased the quality and also reduced our debugging time.
- I wrote documentation for the IT recruitment process to help HR find suitable candidates.
- To lower the development time of each project. I introduced the idea of having an internal coding library and documentation of company standard projectstructures and techstacks. This expanded the knowledge sharing between the developers.

Teaching Assistant Sept. 2020 – May 2021

University: KTH Royal Institute of Technology

Stockholm

• Helped KTH students with programming and graded their projects. Learned how to communicate efficiently.

#### **EXTRACURRICULAR**

## **Boardmember in Bright at KTH**

July 2022 - June 2023

Role: Head of IT

KTI

• During my year, we tripled the amount of members and we became the biggest association at KTH, landing at 1127 members. I also built a new website and ticketing system to charge attendees for our events.

## Diverse voluntary roles during my time at KTH:

**Sept. 2017 - June 2023** 

Organisations: The chapter of Media Technology & The Chapter of OPEN at KTH

KTH

- **Project Leader for the reception**: I learned project management by recruiting a team of 50 students. Planned and coordinated a 4 week long reception for 150 newly admitted students to KTH.
- **Webmaster for the reception**: Lead a group of 4 people with the task of developing and maintaining a website for the reception of the newly admitted students. We used AWS, Flask & Reactjs for the website.
- **PR Manager in Metaspexet**: Led a group of 6 people. Our task was to market "Metaspexet 2019: Elementary", which is an interactive theater at KTH. We sold out all 460 tickets.
- **Event Manager in the Business Relations Committee**: Contacted companies in the IT/management business and planned events with them and our students. We created a total of 4 events.
- Web Developer at Medias Branchdag: Developed the website for the annual fair day. I worked with Reactis and TypeScript.
- Accountant: I reviewed the management of the organisation "Sektionen för Medieteknik" at KTH.

#### **SKILLS**

**Programming Languages**: Python, Java, C, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, SQL, Cypress **Developer Tools**: VS Code, Google Cloud Platform, Android Studio, Firebase, Expo Go **Technologies/Frameworks**: ReactJS, NextJS, Tailwind, Git, Cypress, WordPress, Figma **Languages**: Swedish, English, Kurdish